Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of New York City Miscellaneous Manuscripts, circa 1614-1933 (bulk 1641-1900) MS 443.19
New-York Historical Society
- Receipt of Charles Nichols for hogshead of Barbados rum (Joseph Allicocke), 1768 March 23 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Receipt for Alexander Stewart for Madeira wine (Clarkson & Seabring), 1768 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Bill of Thomas Harris on John Nicholl, Esq., at New Port, 1768 June 3 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  3 pounds, 3 shillings for Henry Remsen
- Receipt for Charles Nichols (Moore & Lynsen), 1769 November 19 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Order for 100 pounds (value of vessel) by Thomas Penington, 1769 January 6 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Weight of Barrels of flour from John Druyn sold to Thomas Marston & Co., 1769 November 12 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Order to give ___ Jonston 1 bead and 1 bond for 2 blankets (William Gabbets), 1769 February 13 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Receipt to James Creighton (Charles Nichols), 1769 June 2 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Inquisition re Elizabeth Sprout has sustained damages of 41 pounds, 1769 August 8 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Power of Attorney by Garret Rapalie to John Dixon, 1769 March 22 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Copy of Order from the King dismissing petition to incorporate the Presbyterian Church in the Province of New York, 1769 August 26 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Agreement re their share of estate of Francis Silvester, signed & sealed by William & Elizabeth Ritchie, 1769 April 22 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  Elizabeth was the widow of Francis Silvester
- Royal Appointment of Whitehead Hicks as Mayor of New York, 1769 October 13 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Receipt of West & Gerard Bancker for pair of Andirons and tongs and shovels for officers (William Gabbets), 1769 February 6 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Pay 200 pounds to John Kennedy for value received (Hugh & Alex Wallace), 1769 September 9 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Delivered to Peter Marselis building materials (Charles Nichols), 1769 August 26 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Pay to the order of Henry Lloyd 50 pounds, 1769 January 2 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  Check signed over to Mr. Penington of value received of Mr. Wessel Van Schaick; also signed Peter Livingston
- New York City Inquisition at House of Walter Brock, 1769 September 4 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  Jacob Starn (?) suffered damages in amount of 12 pounds, 15 shillings
- Resolution of the Inhabitants of the City of New York RE: Regarding cruel treatment by troops stationed in the city; with list of names, 1770 January 17 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- New York City Inquisition at House of Walter Brock, 1770 May 27 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  John D. Crimsheir (?) suffered damages in the amount of 3 pounds, 15 shillings
- Bill of Exchange for 100 pounds to Pay to Mr. Wessel Van Schaick (Messrs. Sargent Chambers & Co., Merchants in London), 1770 August 24 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Bill of Exchange for 100 pounds to Pay to Mr. Wessel Van Schaick (Messrs. Sargent Chambers & Co., Merchants in London), 1770 August 24 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Order to Mr. John Collins, New York (Charles Nichols), 1770 March 10 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Order to be shipped includes 2 Bibles, 2 Prayer Books, etc
- Receipt for Jamaican spirits and French brandy for Mr. Samuel Govenour (Charles Nichols), 1770 April 18 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Receipt for Mr. Evert Bancker (Thomas Ludlow), 1770 December 12 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Receipt for wine & sherry for Charles Nichols (Greg Cunningham), 1770 June 12 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Account of what James Carr bought for Charles Nichols from William Coventry, 1770 September 17 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Account of Edward Laight (Charles Nichols), 1770 September - November (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Edward Laight bought nails, brads, sundry locks
- Receipt of payment of 120 pounds from Walter Rutherford to Colonel James Robertson, 1770 May 21 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Account of Anthony Bleecker, 1770 July 6 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Charles Nichols paid to Anthony Bleecker 3 pounds, 4 shillings for lace jacket and black silk
- Order to Survey eastside of Lake Champlain, signed by Cadwallader Colden, Lt. Governor, 1770 June 6 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Letter to Colonel Bradstreet from Richard Maitland, Dep. Agt. Gen. of the English Forces, 1770 April 25 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Letter enclosing Proclaimation by King RE: pardoning of Deserters to be posted in Albany
- Copy of Letter to Friends of Just Liberty in Philadelphia, original dated 1770 March 10, from Sons of Liberty in New York (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Indenture of Farquhar McPherson as apprentice to Francis Panton, Barber, for seven years, 1770 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Citation to Executors of the Estate of Peter Stymets to Render an Inventory, 1770 May 22 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Indenture in consideration of marriage of Thomas Oakes and Elshe Monfort, 1771 May 14 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Marriage and disposition of possessions upon death
- List of People granted land in Ulster & Albany counties, 1771 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Petition of Thomas Jansen, Jr. and William Decker to Governor of New York, Earl of Dunmore, 1771 May 6 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Petition to grant land between two tracts and a small slip between a meadow and a farm about 20 acres – near Shawangunk
- Receipt of Sgt. McPherson for articles for party of Invalids of the 60th Regiment, 1771 October 2 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Billet from D.P. Scot to William Banzer (?) for money due, 1771 May 3 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- A true copy of Minutes of meeting of Council held at Fort George on May 1, 1771 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Petition before council of Stephen DeLancey, John DeLancey, Daniel Harris, James Babcock, William Haight, James Meade, Samuel Gardiner and Daniel Harris, Jr. for thirty thousand acres in Albany County
- New York City Inquisition re Isaac Wynants sustained damages of two pounds, 1772 February 10 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Writ of Appraisement and Return in Andrew Elliot and Lambert Moore v. 19 Casks and 5 Chests of Tea, 1 Cask of Blue Powder and 1 Cask of Brimstone, 1772 January 23 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  David Abeel, Benjamin Blagge, and Dirck Brinkerhoff, Majesty's appraisers
- New York City Inquisition re William Butler, 1773 January 29 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Jury of 12 men determined William Butler sustained damages of 23 pounds
- New York City Inquisition re George Harison sustained damages of 7 pounds, 1773 March 22 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- New York City Inquisition re Jonas Phillips of 8 pounds, 1773 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Order signed by Stephen Chase, Post Rider, to pay certain monies to Elizabeth Hazard out of wages as Post Rider, 1773 April 7 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Addressed to John Antill, Postmaster of New York
- A General Account of the Exportation from New York between Nov. 1, 1773 and Nov. 1, 1774, 1773-1774 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Including the number of vessels employed and their tonnage
- Petition of Charles Mair and William Anderson to Governor Tryon of New York to grant them portion of land allotted to non-commissioned officers., 1773 November 11 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  Land in County of Charlotte, township of Socialborough
- New York City Inquisition re James Cole and John Wirts (?) sustained damages of 20 pounds, 1773 December 4 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- New York City Inquisition re James Cole sustained damages of 13 pounds, 1773 December 4 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Council held at Ft. George pleased to grant 200 acres to each Charles Mair and William Anderson of land located in Ulster County, 1773 December 15 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Promissory note to pay for wall at Whitehall Slip by subscribers, Governor Tryon, Leonard Lispenard, John Martin, Charles Nicoll, Edward Nicoll, John Schuyler, Mary Barkly, 1773 July 19 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Summons issued to Pieter Van Vranken, John Van Vranken, Johan Cloet and Jacob Van Voorst to give testimony in the case of John and Deborah Sanders and Ryan Schermerhorn, Daniel Fort, Rykert R. Van Vranken and Dirck Van Vranken, 1774 April 13 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Case involved Trespass and ejection; signed by George Clarke, Secretary of State and Peter Silvester, Attorney
- General Account of the Exportation from New York from Jan 1, 1774 to Jan 1, 1775; General Account of the Importation into the Port of New York (Two Reckonings of the Trade of New York), 1774-1775 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Includes number of vessels employed and amount of tonnage
- Plan of Plot of Land purchased by Governor Tryon from Thomas and Margaret Ellison, 1774 April (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Copy delivered to Governor Tryon before he sailed to England
- Plan of lots lying near Whitehall Slip and in South Ward, surveyed in 1774 by G. (Gerard) B. (Bancker) C.S., 1774 November 10 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Lots by Water and Moore Streets owned by Rutgers, Livingston, DeLancey, Co. Moore and Thomas Ellison
- Copy of the Resolutions of New York made July 14, 1774, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  10 Resolutions – To support King George III but view with grief some lat acts of Parliament; Blocking the Boston Port is arbitrary; Destruction of Tea not only Motive for bringing distress on its people; To assist a sister colony in distress; To propose a congress of delegates from different colonies; To leave to this Congress to determine mode of action; That our inestimable Rights and Liberties supersede all others; That a non importation partially observed like the last would answer no good purpose; That the delegates of the New Congress pledge themselves for the Good Conduct; Thanks to citizens of Great Britain who support Colonies
- 27 Minutes of the New York Revolutionary Committee (Committee of Correspondence), May 16-Nov 15, 1774 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Includes Minutes, Resolutions, Letters
- James Duane's Draft of Governor Tryon's Report on the State and Condition of the Province of New York, 1774 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Report is over 100 pages
- 1774-1775 Letters (28) from Lord Dartmouth to the Governors of New York (Hand copied), undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Consideration from Thomas and Margaret Ellison to Governor Tryon 350 pounds – All that Tenement and lot of ground, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Plot in South Ward bounded northerly by Pearl Street, westerly and southerly by small street that separates it from Battery and easterly by lot owned by Sylvester Morris
- A Plan of so much of the ground, purchased by Governor Tryon, surveyed by G. (Gerard) B. (Bancker) C.S., 1775 September 8 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Copy of a Resolution from the Minutes of the Provincial Congress, signed by Robert Benson, Secretary, 1775 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Letter from John Browne & Peter Boyer to Elbridge Gerry, 1775 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Regarding donation from "our sympathizing bretheren of that city for the relief and Employment of the Sufferers in this town by the operation of the Port Bill."
- A True Copy of a Resolution of the Common Council, 1775 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- 1775 Correspondence between William Tryon, Governor of New York, and Whitehead Hicks, Mayor of New York City, 1775 October (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Resolution to Manufacture Muskets and Bayonets, made in Provincial Congress, 1775 December 15 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  Agreement between Col. Alexander McDougall and Peter Curtenius (Provincial Congress) and Cornelius Atherton to manufacture muskets and bayonets; Contract of 350 pounds; signed John Kesson, Secretary, Alexander McDougall, Peter Curtenius, Comfort Sands
- Two Broadsides – A General Association Agreed to dated April 29, 1775; Resolution of Provincial Congress to recommend all counties to appoint County Committees and to sign General Association, 1775 April 29; 1775 May 29 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  Undersigned citizens agreed to adopt whatever measures recommended by our Provincial Convention until Reconciliation between Great Britain and America; Counties appoint County Committees and sign General Association signed by Philip Van Brugh Livingston, President
- 1776 Accounts of State of New York to Various Persons for Care of Poor Refugees from New York City (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Letter from Provincial Congress to Peter Livingston, 1776 March 24 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  Advance on loan to pay contingent expenses to support United Colonies against attempts by British to enslave the continent
- List of British Troops Occupying New York Houses, 1776 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- A True Copy of Resolution of Provincial Congress signed by Robert Benson, Secretary, 1776 March 8 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  Port Master shall accompany provisions or supplies to a Ship of War or a Governor's Ship on board and take only such persons necessary to navigate ship; persons on ship will not disclose any such fortifications erected in defense of colony
- Unanimous Resolution of Provincial Congress to appoint Comfort Sands Auditor General, 1776 July 24 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Certification of Encampment, Regiment Donop (Hessians) encamped at Mr. Jones' Farm in Bloomingdale, 1776 September 21-December 5 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Resolution of the Provincial Congress, 1776 March 14 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  All males capable of fatigue (including all "negro" men) be employed on fortifications of the city
- 1776 Proceedings in New York in re: Disaffected Persons (Box 4, Folder 48)
  These proceedings were copied by Berthold Fernow; Originals destroyed in fire in 1911
- Minutes of a Commission to Investigate the Causes of the 1776 Fire in New York City, 1783 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  This is a lengthy report of 1783 concerning the great fire in New York City in September of 1776. Also includes a deposition by Dr. Charles Ingles.
- Accounting of Window Leads in New York City (2 folders), 1776 (Box 4, Folder 50/51)
- Resolution of Provincial Congress, 1776 September 7 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  Take all brass knockers from doors in New York City sent to Newark, NJ to be weighed and valued
- Royal Appointment of Whitehead Hicks as Justice of Supreme Court, 1776 February 14 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Includes seal
- Letter from Provincial Congress of New York (Nathaniel Woodhull) to Convention of Virginia (Edmund Pendleton), 1776 June 6 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Received copy of resolutions by the Convention of Virginia; Provincial Congress will adopt every measure that promotes Union
- Letter from New York Committee of Safety (Pierre Van Cortlandt, Chairman) to James Livingston, 1776 January 18 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Strongly requesting that James Livingston allow the shipbuilders to use a spot on his property for public service; your refusal rends you obnoxious to the friends of Liberty
- Appraisement of Sundry Arms taken from Non-Associators by the General Committee, 1776 June 11 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Arms include pistols, muskets, guns, bayonets and swords
- Bearer Mrs. Kingston, signed Nicholas Bayard, Henry Rutgers, 1776 July 6 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Letter from Moses Bukley, Chairman of the District Committee of Fredericksburgh, to the President of the Council of Safety of the State of New York regarding the transportation of rebels and traitors, 1777 December 21 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- A copy from the minutes (dated 1777 September 24) regarding a Petition by John Williams, Chairman of the Committee of Charlotte County, and 85 other inhabitants, signed by John M. Kelson, Clerk, House of Assembly, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Petition prays for assistance in their distress of being driven from their land by the enemy
- Resolution of the Representatives of the State of New York that Comfort Sands is appointed Pay Master, signed by Abraham Ten Broeck, Chairm, 1777 April (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Pay off payrolls of Militia of Counties of Duchess, Ulster, West Chester and Orange
- Report by New York Committee of Safety on care of poor people, Signed by Abraham Ten Broeck, President, 1777 February 25 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Order to pay John Thomas, Jr., Esq. 176 pounds for keeping 23 poor people. List on back of poor people
- State of Non-Commissioned Officers and Privates in the Regiments of the State of New York, signed by Tim Pickering, Adj. Gen., 1777 December 29 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Resolution of The Committee of the Convention of the State of New York vesting full power in Brig. General George Clinton to call out Militia, 1777 March 25 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Letter from The Committee of the Convention of the State of New York to Lt. Jeremiah Hunter regarding wheat he has seized from John Griffin, a member of the Militia, 1777 February 21 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Committee requests that the sale of wheat be postponed until further notice
- Extract from the Minutes of The Committee of the Convention of the State of New York; Order that every member without leave from the Convention be sent for by express at his own expense, 1777 April 4; 1777 April 11 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Indenture by John, a "Negro" Man, to John Dease to apprentice as a servant for 7 years, 1778 September 8 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Request of Matthew Nicoll/Charles Nicoll to pay Evert Bancker 54 pounds in New York currency for value received, 1778 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Copy of a petition (dated 1778 January 28) from Freeholders and Inhabitants of Cumberland County to the Governor, the Senate and the General Assembly of New York, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Petition regarding the State of Vermont and its enactment of laws that bind the inhabitants of Cumberland County
- Objections of the Council constituted to revise all bills about to be passed into law by the Legislature to the Bill entitled "An Act to prevent the exportation of flour meal and grain out of this state", 1778 February 20 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Objection raised to Committee on Safety as not representative of the people and thus cannot make laws
- Permission for Mr. Stephen Lush and Mr. Sam Dodge to pass to Elizabethtown by way of Staten Island, 1778 February 4 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Certificate that Brig. Polly employed by Majesty's Service in the Commissary General Department, signed by David Laird, agent, 1778 January 28 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Blockade of New York: Permission given by Command of the Admiral for Sloop Fanny to pass and repass within the protection of his Majesty's ships for the sole purpose of supplying fuel to city, 1778 September 22 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Proclamation of the Forfeiture of Property of Loyalists with List of Names, 1779 October 22 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- MS. Leaves from Hutchins Almanack, 1779 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  Information on ships passages
- Recognizance that Commissioners of the Continental Loan Office owe to the people of New York 100,000 pounds, signed by Robert Yates, 1779 November 2 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  Commissioners were Abraham Yates, Killian de Ridder, Jacob Lansing, Jacob Bogart and Matthew Vischer
- Act to authorize the several county committees within New York to procure a supply of shoes and stockings for the Troops Raised, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Petition of Isaac Bellknap to the State Legislature regarding payment for flour, 1779 February 11 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Letter from Henry Frankin/ Smith Ramadge rendered to the Office of Police – Pell Birks should pay Edward Guolo for two pounds of butter, 1779 July 15 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- List of Inhabitants of South Street, White Hall and Exchange Slip, 1779 August 29-September 7 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Petition of Gerard Bancker to State Assembly of New York asking to be discharged from his Office as Treasurer of the State of New York, 1779 February 10 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Permission given by the Superintendent General of Police to Samuel James, Esq. to pass freely between New York City and Long Island, signed by Matthews, Mayor, 1779 July 31 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- List of Jurors who find for the Defendant in Lawrence Kerwin v. Thomas Doyle, 1799 June 3 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  Signed by 12 jurors, including Gerret Van Gelder, Edward Meeks, Jonas Humbert
- Constitution of A Scottish Presbyterian Praying Society, 1779 July 4 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Note from C.N. Taylor to W. Baniker, RE: estimate of value, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Royal Order to the judge or deputy of the Vice Admiralty Court of New York enclosing order by His Majesty to remedy inconveniences that have arisen by Appeals in Prize Causes not being prosecuted in a reasonable time, 1780 December 21 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Royal Order respecting the mode of proceeding in cases of appeal in Prize Causes, 1780 December 15 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Copy of Royal Instructions (dated 1780 December 20) given to Judges in Admiralty Courts respecting the modes of proceeding on the Captains of all ships and goods belonging to the States General of the United Provinces, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Extract from "The Act for the further direction of the State Agent passed 22 November 1781" New York State (Box 5, Folder 71)
- Resolution for People of a certain district lying between the west line of the State of Vermont and the North River regarding jurisdiction of District between Western boundary of Vermont and North River., 1781 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  Confusion as to whether in Vermont or New York. Signed by many people
- Rosters of City Guards for Hanover Square for certain dates, 1782 (Box 5, Folder 70)
- Order by 3rd Battalion, Isaac Low and John Linch, to alternatively attend Bunker Hill every morning, 1782 March 17 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  Men who choose not to work themselves may send substitute
- Morning Report of Captain, Ten Barrack of First New York Regiment, 1782 June 30 (Box 5, Folder 68)
- Court Martial of Mr. Jones because his two cows had gotten free and damaged the gardens of the Regiment, 1782 August 3 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  Mr. Jones was commanded to pay 2 pounds 13 shillings
- New York State Blank Military Forms related to census, undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
- Certification by Jacob Lansing, Commissary of Musters for the State of New York, that Peter Curtenus hired an able body man, David Culver, to serve in his place, 1782 September 14 (Box 5, Folder 70)
- Appraisal by Nathaniel Wright and Moses Winter of Timber taken from the Estate of Nicholas Jones at Bloomingdale since 1776, 1783 July 16 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  Seven hundred tree stumps – Oak, Maple, Beech, Ash, Birch, and Elm
- Resolution of the Legislature of New York regarding bounty land to officers in war, 1783 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  Copy(?) watermark has later date than 1783 - 1798(?)
- New York State (Henry Windall, Sheriff of the County of Albany) List of persons indicted for adhering to the enemies of this state, 1783 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Estimate of Necessary items for Alms House agreed to by the Commissioners of the Alms House, 1784 June 28 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Needs included Cord wood, wine, rum, tea, butter, brown sugar, tobacco
- Petitions of Anthony and Leonard Bleeker to the Legislature of New York re granting licenses to individuals in Auctioneering Business, 1784 January 10, 21 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  After the war, petitioners asking for license to return to their business
- Petition to James Duane, Esquire, Mayor of New York City, by undersigned to allow John Tuner to drive a cart, 1784 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  Petition signed by Comfort Sands and 8 others
- Petition by William Van Deursen to permit Edward Lowrear, A friend and well wisher to the American Army, to drive cart, 1784 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 72)
- Letter from St. John, Frenchman living in New York, to Mr. DuMarbois, 1784 July 6 (Box 5, Folder 72)
- Appointment of John Jay, Egbert Benson, Walter Livingston, John Lansing, Jr., Zephania Platt to represent New York in US Congress, signed by John Hathorn, Speaker, 1784 October 24 (Box 5, Folder 65)
- Petition to permit Matthew Granger, who was imprisoned on a prisoner ship, to drive a cart, Signed by Gerardus Hardenbrook, Jr. and 4 others, 1784 April 19 (Box 5, Folder 72)
- Statement regarding rent that was to be paid by Mr. Price and Mr. Ray, undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
  Statement writer had left New York with orders for Dr. Onderdunk (?) to rent his house
- Certification by Thomas Bilby, Captain in the Royal Fusilear Regiment, that mortgage between Margaret Johnston and George Elsworth paid, 1784 June 16 (Box 5, Folder 73)